A Guide to the Governor William B. Giles Executive Papers, 1827-1830
Library of Virginia
Other noteworthy items include: proclamations by the governor & lieutenant governor offering rewards for the apprehension of escaped convicts (1827 March 20 & 22, April 7 & 16, June 4, July 28, Aug. 11, Sept. 29, Oct. 6 & 16; 1828 March 13, April 8, 24, & 29, July 8, Sept. 10, Nov. 21, Dec. 9; 1829 March 3, 27, & 31, Sept. 15, Oct. 1, 2, & 10); the contract of Herman Boye for the publication of four hundred copies of the map of Virginia and eight hundred copies of the reduced map (1827 May 1); the proclamation authorizing the Manchester & Petersburg Turnpike Company to demand & receive tolls (1827 May 14); the report of the Committee to select books for the Public Library & making purchases (1827 Oct. 24); the certificate of copyright for the reduced map of Virginia created by Herman Boye (1827 Oct. 31); a certificate of qualification by Joseph Tate, Mayor of Richmond, for William B. Giles as governor (1827 Dec. 12); a list of free negroes in the Penitentiary sentenced for transportation (1828 Jan. 17); proposal to borrow from the Executive the money belonging to the Washington Monument Fund (1828 March); an estimate for fitting up the General Court Room for a library (1828 March 21); the contract of Samuel Shepherd & Co. to print 250 copies of the journals of the Senate & House of Delegates for the year 1776 (1828 March 28); certificates of qualification of Lawson Burfoot as treasurer (1828 April 8, 1829 Feb. 6, & 1830 Jan. 23); an ordnance of the Common Council of Richmond relating to the Public Square (1828 April 10); an estimate by Bosher & Brown to execute the wood work for fitting up the Library in the Capitol (1828 April 19); advice of the Council requiring the Captain of the Public Guard inspect the Capitol once per month and to make use of the Public Guard to keep the Capitol clean & in good repair (1828 April 22); certificates, will, and deeds regarding the land of John Mayo in Henrico County which was purchased by John Powell from Samuel Price & James Vaughan (1828 May 5); the contract of Bosher & Brown to fit up the room in the Capitol for a Library Room (1828 May 7); the advice of Council to close the western side of the Public Square for the preservation of the trees (1828 May 27); the notice of the Directors of the Western Lunatic Hospital that the institution will be ready for the reception of patients on July 25 (1828 June 20); the proclamation regarding the results of the vote for a Convention (1828 Sept. 1); advice of Council that the Library Committee be authorized to employ an agent to purchase books for the Public Library and to employ a competent person to paint the Library Room (1828 Aug. 22); a statement re. a summary of expenditures for the map of the state (1828 Oct. 12); a proclamation re. the election of electors of President & Vice-President of the United States (1828 Nov. 19); the certificate of qualification of William B. Giles as governor (1828 Dec. 11); a remonstrance of the states in favor of the tariff adopted by the Georgia State Legislature (1828 Dec. 20); an ordinance relating to the Public Square in the city of Richmond and the yard of the City Hall (1829 March 13); a report of the committee appointed to draft rules for the Penitentiary encl. rules & regulations for the government of the Penitentiary (1829 May 26); a report of the committee to enquire in what parts of the Commonwealth are arms most wanted to guard against insurrection from slaves (1829 Aug. 4); a report of the committee on the list of books transmitted by the Librarian (1829 Aug. 18); a proclamation re. an election to replace Ellyson Currie, a member of the Convention (1829 Sept. 4); a proclamation declaring the Schooner Armada under quarantine due to small pox (1830 Jan. 5); a proclamation to extend the quarantine of the Schooner Armada (1830 Jan. 18); and a proclamation that the amended Constitution be published once a week for three successive months (1830 Jan. 18).
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically by date of document with undated items arranged to the rear.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
Flournoy, H. W., CALENDAR OF VIRGINIA STATE PAPERS, January 1, 1808-December 31, 1835, VOL. X, Richmond: James E. Goode, Printer, 1892.
Contents List
- William B. Giles Executive Papers
- 1827
  - March
    - 5-17 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 19-25 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 26-31 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - April
    - 1-20 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 21-30 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - May
    - 1-15 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 17-31 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - June
    - 1-11 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 11-20 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 21-30 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - July
    - 1-10 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 11-20 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 21-31 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - August
    - 1-10 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 11-20 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 22-31 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - September
    - 1-15 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 16-30 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - October
    - 1-15 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 16-31 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - November
    - 1-11 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 12-19 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 20-30 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - December
    - 1-15 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 16-31 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- 1828
  - January
    - 1-10 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 11-26 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 27-31 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - February
    - 1-8 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 11-29 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - March
    - 1-11 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 12-25 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - 19-25 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - April
    - 1-10 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - 11-21 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - 22-29 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - May
    - 1-10 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - 11-20 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - 22-31 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - June
    - 1-10 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - 11-20 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - 23-30 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - July
    - 1-11 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 12-31 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - July
    - 1-15 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - 16-31 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - September
    - 1-15 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 16-30 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - October
    - 1-15 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - 17-31 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - November
    - 1-15 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - 17-21 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - 22-29 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - December
    - 1-10 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 11-31 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- 1829
  - January
    - 1-15 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 16-31 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - February
    - 2-10 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - 11-29 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - March
    - 2-20 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - 21-31 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - April
    - 1-15 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - 16-30 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - May
    - 1-15 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - 16-30 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - June
    - 1-15 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 16-30 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - July
    - 1-20 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - 21-31 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - August
    - 3-15 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - 16-31 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - September
    - 1-15 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - 16-30 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - October (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - November
    - 2-15 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - 16-30 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - December
    - 1-15 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 16-31 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- 1830
  - January
    - 2-15 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - 16-28 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - February
    - 1-10 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - 13-29 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - March
    - 1-4 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Oversized (Clamshell Box)
  - 1827
    - March 31 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - April 1 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - April 14 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - April 25 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - May 23 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - June 5 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - July [N.D.] (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Nov. 5 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Dec. 15 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - 1828
    - Jan. 4 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - April 1 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - May 10 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - May 16 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - July 8 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - July 8 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Dec. 1 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Dec. 1 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - 1829
    - Jan. 1 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Feb. 20 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - March 24 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - April 21 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - June 2 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - June 18 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Oct. 1 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - 1830
    - Feb. 15 (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Oversized (Newspaper Box)
  - 1827
    - April 16 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Oct. 30 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - 1828
    - March 28 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - March 31 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - May 5 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - May 28 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Nov. 7 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Dec. 18 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - 1829
    - May 22 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Aug. [N.D.] (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Oct. 31 (Box 10, Folder 11)